lunar sabbaths or weekly sabbaths that's
what we're going to be tackling next
stay tuned
[Music]
okay guys I'm not gonna spend uh too
long on this so I've gotten uh several
questions asking about the difference
between a lunar Sabbath and the weekly
Sabbath uh in fact the question is more
specifically as to whether uh there is
even a weekly Sabbath that the true
Sabbath is a lunar Sabbath versus a
weekly Sabbath so we're going to take a
look at that in this presentation again
it's not going to be too long
um we're just going to go ahead and jump
right in so let's go to the screen so
the the idea is that
the true Sabbath is really a lunar
Sabbath and the weekly Sabbath uh
meaning Friday Sundown to Saturday
Sundown is actually a product of
deception a product of a change from
um the Hebrew calendar to a Gregorian
calendar
again I'm not going to spend too much
time on this I just want to show you uh
two points in particular so let's go
ahead and let's read the Commandment
first of all the Bible says in Exodus 20
verse 8.
remember the Sabbath day to keep it holy
six days shout out labor and do all thy
work but the seventh day is the Sabbath
of the Lord thy God in it thou shall not
do any work thou nor thy son nor thy
daughter thy man servant nor thy maid
servant nor thy cattle nor thy stranger
that is within thy Gates for in six days
the Lord made Heaven and Earth the sea
and all that in in them is and rested
the seventh day wherefore the Lord
blessed the Sabbath day and hallowed it
so the question here is really simple
is this talking about the seventh day of
the month or is it talking about the
seventh day of the week right if if it's
the seventh day of the month it's a
lunar Sabbath instead of what is
believed as a weekly Sabbath
so in order to really get to the bottom
line of this because there's a whole lot
of complicated arguments when it comes
to presenting uh the the lunar Sabbath
and honestly
if
salvation depended upon rightly
calculating the lunar Sabbath
uh there would be a lot of people
that would just be able to claim
ignorance like really really be able to
claim ignorance
um
we know that salvation is not based on a
day so don't get me wrong salvation is
is
accomplished by what Christ did on the
cross for us but as a result of that we
obey him because of what he did for us
right we we keep his Commandments
because we love him and this is one of
those Commandments so now the question
is again
is this commandment
a Commandment that
um
requires us to figure out
the motion
and the movements of the Moon in order
to keep this commandment correctly
all right
let's look at Leviticus chapter 23 we're
just going to go to two verses really
one chapter Leviticus 23 we're going to
stay here and then we're going to go
back to the creation week and then we're
going to wrap this up so in Leviticus 23
verse 4 the Bible says these are the
feasts of the Lord even holy
convocations which you shall Proclaim in
their seasons now I want you to notice
this in the 14th day of the first month
and I want you to notice
the Bible is about to list these feast
days
that are basically calculated
by the Moon by the lunar cycle so it
says here in the 14th day of the first
month you can translate that word month
as Moon so in the first 14th day of the
first moon or month if you will at the
evening at evening shall be the Lord's
Passover
and on the 15th day of the same month or
on the 15th day of the moon is the Feast
of unleavened bread unto the Lord seven
days you must eat unleavened bread we're
gonna go to verse 23.
the Lord spake unto Moses saying Speak
unto the children of Israel saying in
the seventh month in the first day of
the month
first day of the Moon
you shall have a Sabbath a memorial of
long of trumpets a holy convocation
you see it again in verse 27 and on the
10th day of this of the seventh month
there shall be a day of atonement it
shall be a holy convocation unto you and
you shall afflict your souls and offer
an offering made by fire unto the Lord
we find it in verse 34 speak unto the
children of Israel saying that the 15th
day of this seventh month
the seventh Moon
shall be the Feast of Tabernacles for
seven days unto the Lord also in the
15th day of the seventh month when you
have gathered in the fruit of your land
you shall keep a feast unto the Lord
Seven Days on the first day shall be a
Sabbath and on the Eighth Day shall be a
Sabbath so what I want you to notice
here is something very specific
um
you will see that when the Lord is
referring to
days that are calculated by the moon
he's using the phrase 15th day of the
seventh month right of the first month
of the third month Etc
um so you'll always see
that it's calculated in connection with
the month or the moon now in the very
same chapter listen we know then that
the Passover unleavened bread first
fruits Pentecost trumpets uh Tabernacles
the day of atonement
are all based on the month on the moon
it tells us there as it's describing the
15th day of the seventh month the tenth
day of the seventh Moon
now I want you to notice how the Sabbath
in the same chapter is described
Leviticus 23 verse 2.
speak unto the children of Israel and
say unto them concerning the Feast of
the Lord which you shall Proclaim to be
holy convocation even these are my
Feasts
six days shall work be done but the
seventh day is the Sabbath of rest now I
want you to know what the text does not
say
it does not say in the seventh day of
the month
it simply says in the seven on the
seventh day the seventh day well the
seventh day of what if he meant the
seventh day of the month he would have
said like he did with the other feasts
of the month he doesn't do that
not in this text in fact nowhere in the
Bible is the Sabbath ever stated as the
seventh day of the month
okay
let's go to Genesis chapter one and I
want you to know this we're almost done
Genesis chapter one Genesis chapter 1
beginning with verse 14.
and God said let there be lights in the
firmament of the heaven to divide the
day from the night and let them be for
signs and for seasons and for days and
for years and let them be for light in
the firmament of the Heavens to give
light upon the Earth and it was so and
God made two great lights so what are
those two great lights the Sun and the
Moon
God made two great lights the greater
light to Rule the Day and the Lesser
light to rule the night he made the
Stars also
and God set them in the firmament of
Heaven to give light upon the Earth and
to rule over the day and over the night
and to divide the light from the
darkness and God saw that it was good
and the evening and the morning were the
fourth day so if I were to ask you a
question
when was the literal first new moon
your answer would be well the first new
moon ever would have been on the fourth
day of creation the very first new moon
was on the fourth day of the week
so what does that mean what does that
tell us the first Sabbath was on the
seventh day not of the month
but of the week but if you're counting
by the new moon then the very first
Sabbath would have been on the third day
of the new month
not the seventh day of the month the
third day of the month and what this
does beloved it's it would throw the
whole calculation
of the seventh day
Sabbath being on the seventh
day of the month
or after the new moon however you choose
to phrase it it throws that whole math
off
the Sabbath
as given by God
was the seventh day not of the month
but of the week
and thus we know that every seven days
you're gonna have the Sabbath again it
had nothing to do with the Moon
it has to do with the weak it had
nothing to do with the month it has to
do with the week so
in order for you to
in order for you to entertain
the idea
that the lunar Sabbath
involved the seventh day Sabbath
well I'm not saying there's no such
thing as a lunar Sabbath what we're
saying is the lunar sabbaths were
Passover unleavened bread first fruits
Pentecost day of atonement Feast of
Tabernacles Feast for trumpets Etc
these were the lunar sabbaths they were
based upon the moon the tenth day of the
Moon
the Sabbath has no
such description connected to it The
Seventh-Day Sabbath it is the seventh
day of the week not of the Moon not of
the month
so in order for us
to even entertain a discussion of the
Sabbath being lunar you would have to
produce a verse
that states
the seventh day of the month referring
to the Sabbath
okay hopefully that's simple enough
um comment in the chat
now listen
I want one thing and one thing only
one verse
that says the seventh day of the month
referring to the Sabbath
one verse
if we can't find that verse this is not
even a discussion
it's not even a discussion
all right
happy hunting and may God bless you as
you continue to come closer and seek
the truth
amen
[Music]